the rep saber barbell may be one of the
most versatile barbells on the market
that you can also find for a budget
friendly price
now you may ask me isn't a barbell just
a barbell
actually no it's not some are meant for
a more traditional style usage like
squatting or bench pressing while others
are meant for olympic style lifting this
saber though it can handle it all
[Music]
what's up everybody it's jake back at it
in the barbing garage gym and in full
review today
i've got the rep fitness saber barbell
in this video i'm going to take you
through everything this bar has to offer
the price some pros and cons and as
always who should buy it and who
shouldn't buy it all right so before we
get started today we have reviewed a
whole lot of barbells on barbin.com so
if you want to explore our top picks
just google barbin best barbells and
find out for yourself if the saber made
our best list
okay so there's a lot that i like about
this barbell this version of the saber
features a black zinc coating giving it
a nice all-black finish which i
personally think looks awesome in your
gym
two it's rated at a thousand pounds
which means you can really load on the
weight for those heavy lifts and three
it comes in both men's and women's sizes
the men's is a shade under 45 pounds as
the women's is about 33 pounds you can
also choose for your bar to come with a
regular or black zinc coating and you
can choose for your bar to come with or
without a center knurling the one we
have here today does not have a center
knurling
there are a few potential cons that i
could see with this barbell while it
does feature an all-purpose medium style
knurling you may find the black zinc
coating does make the saber a little
less
grippy so if you do get some sweaty
hands while you're working out you may
want to utilize some chalk and second
the tensile strength of the saver is
rated at 150 000 psi pencil strength is
essentially how much load the bar can
handle before it begins to crack or
fracture 150 000 is a little bit on the
lower end of the spectrum and there are
other options available out there with a
similar price range that are rated up to
230 000 psi
[Music]
okay so since the saber is technically
customizable you will notice a few
pricing options the 15 kilogram bar only
features a regular zinc finish and does
not come with a center knurl this bar is
going to cost you 200. the 20 kilogram
bar whether or not you have the center
knurling with a regular zinc finish is
going to cost you 230 dollars and with
the black zinc bar you don't have the
option for a center knurling but you'll
still notice that price jump up to 260
dollars
these prices land right in the middle
compared to similar competition and
offers good value for those looking for
a high quality barbell that's versatile
enough to handle various workouts in
your home gym when you check out you'll
notice that you have the option to make
four interest-free payments through
paypal instead of paying everything up
front but keep in mind these prices will
vary depending on which bar you choose
the build for your bar is really going
to depend on which one you decide to go
with the 15 kilogram bar has a diameter
of 25 millimeters with 12 and a half
inch loading sleeves now the 20 kilogram
bar has a 28 millimeter diameter and 16
inch loading sleeves the 20 kilogram bar
is also longer overall just over 87
inches and the 15 kilogram bar is around
79 inches
either way they're both rated at a
thousand pounds with a tensile strength
rating of 150 000 psi now you may be
surprised by how many accessories do
come with the barbell the sabre features
a moderate
mountain grip knurling which is ideal
for high rep high frequency training the
20 kilogram bar does have the option for
center knurling which could be ideal for
back squats anything with a suitcase
grip or maybe even for your spotter
while you're bench pressing but keep in
mind if you are wanting to work in
olympic style and crossfit style lifts
that center knurling could irritate your
skin by how frequently it rubs against
you since the saber does have a zinc
coating you may notice less corrosion
resistance than say a fully stainless
steel bar wood but as long as you
lubricate it it should stay in good
shape and may even potentially last you
a lifetime it is worth noting that the
saber does have smooth loading sleeves
which may lead your weight plates
sliding a little bit more than say one
with grooves in it
but they're also quieter and you can
always lock your weight plates in with a
collar the sleeves are also coated in
zinc and they use a bronze bushing to
allow the bar to spin with ease bronze
bushings are often found in versatile
barbells like these as they create a
smooth and controlled spin they're less
expensive than barbells that utilize
bearings and they degrade at a slower
rate
all right so we're going to walk you
through the saber barbell now as you can
see ours does have that nice black zinc
finish which i think makes it look
really cool but remember the black zinc
does not feature that center knurling
now and also as we mentioned the
knurling on this bar is more on the
moderate side and comes with that
mountain grip style
as well as the double knurling marks
which is pretty standard in practice as
it allows you to see your widest grip
possible for your lifts if we come over
here and look at the sleeves you'll
notice the bronze bushings right here
which really allow the sleeves to spin
freely
and also
this is a smooth pattern on these
sleeves it makes it really easy to load
and unload your plates
but you may notice that your plates
might wiggle around and move around a
little bit while you're lifting but
if it's something you're worried about
you can always pop on a weight collar
slide it on
lock it into place and that weight plate
is not going anywhere
so who should buy this barbell well the
saber is really a great option for
virtually anyone especially beginners
that are looking for a knurling that
won't necessarily tear up your hands and
anyone who's looking for a bar that's as
versatile as they come with a high
quality build and comes at a reasonable
price this is a good place to start who
shouldn't buy the saber barbell well if
you're a power lifter and you want a bar
with a very aggressive grip this may not
be the one for you second if you do live
in a humid environment you might find
that the zinc coating does not offer as
much rust protection as a stainless
steel bar can and third the tensile
strength on the saber is on the lower
end of the spectrum while it is a high
quality build that really allows you to
load on heavy weight there are other
options available with the higher
tensile rating
well that's all there is to it for the
rep fitness saber barbell this is a
truly customizable bar thanks to the
size weight and knurling there's
virtually an option available for anyone
whether you're wanting to cross train
olympic style lift or maybe even just
squat and bench press the sabre can
handle it this is a high quality build
at a great price and is a good option
for both beginner and intermediate
weight lifters but if you are on the
elite side of things you may want to
consider a higher end barbell that rep
fitness offers as well as rogue or even
a lego thanks for watching everyone i
hope this video gave you some more
insight on what this barbell has to
offer i'm gonna go get a lift in now but
keep an eye out for my next video and in
the meantime search barbind rep fitness
saber barbell and you can read more on
what we discussed in this video and
maybe even learn more see you next time
[Music]
you